# Taiye Ajimati

# **Front-End Developer**

★ taiyeajimati@gmail.com in linkedin C Github ⊕ Portfolio

\*\*Tolion C Github ⊕ Portfolion C Github ⊕ Portfolion

\*\*Tolion C Github ⊕ Portfolion C Github ⊕ Portfolion

\*\*Tolion C Github

#### **ABOUT ME**

An experienced front-end developer with over 3 years of practical experience in web development and product design. Over the years, I have worked as a Graphic and product designer creating visually appealing products for small and large firms.

I am passionate about building accessible and responsive web applications using React is, JavaScript, CSS, TailwindCSS, Sass, and SQL while managing my code base using version control platforms like GitHub.

#### RELEVANT SKILLS

# **Programming Languages**

Javascript (ES6), HTML, CSS/Sass, TailwindCSS, Python

#### **Libraries & Frameworks**

React, Node is, TailwindCSS, Next is

#### **Tools & Platforms**

Github, Wordpress, Vercel

#### Design

Figma, Adobe xd, Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign

#### **EDUCATION**

# **B.Eng** Computer Engineering

Federal University of Technology, Minna Niger-State.

2012-2017

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

# **Freelance Front-End Developer**

#### Presently

Presently working as a freelance front-end developer and constantly looking out for opportunities and projects that requires my skills and expertise in developed an accessible and scalable software products.

# Web/UI Designer (PT/Contract)

@ Sprout Digital Development

Nov. 2019 - Till date

### Web Developer/ICT Assistant

**@ Sprout Digital Development** 

March 2018 - Sept. 2019

Job Description:

- Created website layout and user interface using standard HTML, CSS & Javascript practices.
- Managed the company's web hosting platform.
- Maintained, expanded, and scaled different clients' websites.
- Created User Interfaces for specialized websites.
- Created graphic designs for web, social media ads & banners, print, and marketing collaterals as required.

# **Graphic Designer**

# @ 240 Media

August. 2012 - Feb.2018

#### Job Description:

- Created custom brand documents for the various clients.
- Created website and social media ads banners, Graphic design using Adobe suite and Coreldraw.
- Incorporate changes recommended by clients or art directors into final designs.
- Review designs for errors before printing or publishing them.

# **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

# codeIT Summer Holiday @ August 2018 - October 2019

Instructional Facilitator - Trained kids under age 16 the basics of programming

# YouthhubAfrica @ October 2019 - December 2019

**Creative Designer** - Volunteered as part of a multimedia team that managed the publicity of a yearly conference organized by YouthhubAfrica.